http://www.ethicaltrade.org/privacy

Skip to main content
Privacy
Policy for: https://ethicaltrade.orgETI is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and your data.Data controller: Ethical Trading Initiative, 8 Coldbath Square, London EC1R 5HLRegistered No. 3578127Third-party linksThis website may include links to third-party websites. Clicking on those links may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy policies.What we collectWhen users of our site subscribe to email updates, request particular resources, book training courses or register interest in our services, we may collect the following information:Name and job titleContact information including organisation name, email address and phone numberDemographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests related to ethical tradeBilling information including details for invoicing purposesHow we handle the information gatheredWe may use the information collected to improve our products and services.We may periodically send emails about new products or resources, special offers, events or other information which we think you may find useful and interesting using the email address which you have provided.Users submitting personal information are asked to give consent for their details to be used in specified ways.When you communicate with us (via email, phone, or via our website), we may maintain a record of your communication.IP address and other trackingWe may collect information about your computer, including operating system and browser type, to inform improvements to the website. User IP addresses shared with Google Analytics are anonymised.CookiesWe use two types of cookies on our website to enhance the user experience:Session Cookies - These are temporary cookies that are used until you leave the site. A session cookie allows your computer to remember each page you’ve visited on our website and it’s necessary for our website to operate efficiently.Persistent Cookies - These remain in the cookie file of your browser for the lifetime of the specific cookieOur cookie policy lists the specific cookies in use on our site.Rating functionalityOn pages where users are invited to rate whether certain content is helpful, we store a hashed version of your IP address to anonymously attribute ratings to visitors. This data is not used for any other purpose.Third partiesWe will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We will, except where required by law, keep your information confidential and will not disclose any such information except where a disclosure is made at your request or with your consent. We reserve the right to disclose personal information you have entered to relevant third parties such as our website developers, where the purpose is to enhance the user experience or general working of the website.  Public forumsUsers of ETI’s website may post comments on blog posts. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit our site. ETI is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.Mailing listWe will send an email every three years to those signed up to our newsletters to ask you to update your details. You can also unsubscribe from our mailing list at any time using the link at the bottom of our emails.Right to be forgottenYou may contact us at anytime to have data deleted. Please see below for contact details of our Data Protection Manager.Changes to our privacy policyAny changes we may make to our privacy policy will be posted on this page.Any concerns?If you have any concerns about privacy in relation to this website, please contact the Data Protection Manager via eti@eti.org.uk This policy was last updated on 22 March 2019.
Footer menu (sub nav)
Cookie policy
Terms and conditions
Get the latest
Subscribe to our email newsletters and stay up to speed on ethical trade.
